Guide to the Leonard H. Swett Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Leonard H. Swett papers
1867-1934
WA MSS S-2708
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.3
(7 boxes)
The papers consist chiefly of family correspondence, photographs, and journals, and include a small amount of financial records. Family correspondence includes letters from Leonard H. Swett to his parents (Leonard Swett and Laura Quigg Swett) that document his travels in the American West in the 1880s, when he worked with the United States Geological Survey. He was stationed at, among other locations, Fort Wingate, New Mexico, BQ (Barbecue) Ranch, Indian Territory, and Albuquerque, New Mexico. Other family papers include records of genealogical research. Personal papers include journals that document Swett's (and an unidentified author's, possibly Swett's) travels in the American West. Photographs, dating chiefly from the late 19th century, depict Leonard H. Swett and family members.
Swett, Leonard H. (Leonard Herbert), b. 1858
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Michael Vinson on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Leonard H. Swett
Leonard Herbert Swett, son of Leonard Swett and Laura Quigg, was born in 1858 in Bloomington, Illinois and traveled extensively in the American West as a surveyor with the United States Geological Survey. He married Rose Maria Skillings (1864-1914) in 1889 and they had at least one child, Laura Rose Swett, born in 1897.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist chiefly of family correspondence, photographs, and journals, and include a small amount of financial records. Family correspondence includes letters from Leonard H. Swett to his parents (Leonard Swett and Laura Swett, nee Quigg) that document his travels in the American West in the 1880s, when he worked with the United States Geological Survey. He was stationed at, among other locations, Fort Wingate, New Mexico, BQ (Barbecue) Ranch, Indian Territory, and Albuquerque, New Mexico. Other family papers include records of genealogical research. Personal papers include journals that document Swett's (and an unidentified author's, possibly Swett's) travels in the American West. Photographs, dating chiefly from the late 19th century, depict Leonard H. Swett and family members.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Family Correspondence and Family Papers, 1867-1934. II. Business Papers, 1876-1929. III. Personal Papers, 1882-1898. IV. Photographs, 1874-1900. V. Other Papers, 1876-1885.
Surveyors -- West (U.S.); Albuquerque (N.M.) -- Description and travel; Indian Territory -- Description and travel; Fort Wingate (N.M.) -- Description and travel; New Mexico -- Description and travel; Photographic prints -- United States -- 19th century; Surveyors -- West (U.S.) -- 19th century; Surveyors -- United States -- 19th century; Swett, Laura Quigg; Swett, Leonard, 1825-1889; Swett, Leonard H. (Leonard Herbert), b. 1858; Sweet family; Geological Survey (U.S.)
- Family Correspondence and Family Papers, 1867-1934; Series I; 1.26; (3 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists chiefly of letters from Leonard H. Swett to his mother and father in the 1870s and 1880s, including letters from the American West, where he worked with the United States Geological Survey. The series also includes other family correspondence and the records of geneaology research apparently carried out by Swett's daughter Laura Rose Swett (born 1897).
  - Leonard H. Swett to mother and father, 1872-1882 (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
  - Mother to Leonard H. Swett, 1879-1886 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ernest H. to Annie Laurie, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Laura Swett to mother, 1910, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Laura Swett to father, 1925-1926, undated (Box 2, Folder 13-16)
  - Laura Swett, incoming correspondence, 1867-1926 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Leonard H. Swett to wife, 1867-1885 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Harold Ashley Burnham (son-in-law) to Leonard H. Swett, 1926, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Rose M. Briggs to Rose, Herbert, and Laura, 1896-1914 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ezra M. Prince to Herbert Swett, 1900-1901 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Laura R. Swett to son, 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Rose M. Swett, incoming correspondence, 1910-1914, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Leonard H. Swett, incoming correspondence, 1880-1925 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1875-1934 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
  - Unsorted correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Genealogy files, 1887-1913, undated (Box 3, Folder 28-34)
- Business Papers, 1876-1929; Series II; 0.21; (1 box)
  Organized by format.
  Series II consists of correspondence relating to Swett's appointment with the United States Geological Survey, receipts for household goods, bank records, and tax returns.
  - Business correspondence, 1885-1913 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Receipts, 1876-1929 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Financial records, 1889-1927 (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
- Personal Papers, 1882-1898; Series III; 0.21; (1 box)
  Series III consists of diaries of Leonard and Rose Swett, unidentified diaries, and an address book of Leonard Swett.
  - Address book, Leonard H. Swett, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Diary of Leonard H. Swett, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Diary of Rose Swett, 1897-1898 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Unidentified diaries, undated (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
- Photographs, 1874-1900; Series IV; 0.21; (1 box)
  Not arranged in any particular order
  Series IV consists of photographs of Leonard H. Swett and family members.
  - Leonard H. Swett, 1874, 1900, undated (Box 6, Folder 44-49)
  - Family members of Leonard H. Swett, 1876-1897, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Other Papers, 1876-1885, undated; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series V consists of a manuscript of a speech about Paris by an unidentified author, a phrenology report on Leonard H. Swett, and other miscellaneous papers.
  - Speech about Paris, manuscript, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Phrenological Character of L. H. Swett, 1876 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Greeting cards, 1882, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Unsorted papers: lists, drawings, etc., undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Envelope and stamp collection, 1885, undated (Box 7, Folder 56-58)
  - Blank paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 59)